Guide to the Max Manes Papers WAG.078
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Max Manes Papers
1929-1954
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Manes, Max
WAG.078
0.25 Linear Feet (1 box)
Max Manes was a leader of the Rank and File group of the United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union, Local 8. Along with other members of Local 8, he led a movement which opposed a special assessment levied in 1933 by international leadership, including president Michael F. Greene and secretary-treasurer Martin Lawlor, and agitated for a special convention, eventually held in October 1936. The collection consists of correspondence, ballots, resolutions, statements, subject files and rank and file newsletters and circulars from UHC Local 42, Local 8, and Local 24.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Max Manes, 1991. The accession number associated with this gift is 1991.010.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Max Manes was a leader of the Rank and File group of the United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union (UHC), Local 8. Along with other members of Local 8, he led a movement which opposed a special assessment levied in 1933 by UHC international leadership, including president Michael F. Greene and secretary-treasurer Martin Lawlor, and agitated for a special convention, eventually held in October 1936.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of correspondence, ballots, resolutions, statements and subject files. Correspondence, statements and credentials from Max Manes are also included in the collection, as are rank and file newsletters and circulars from UHC Local 42, Local 8, and Local 24. Of particular significance are subject files relating to the Millinery and Hatters Committee for [Henry] Wallace and the National Industrial Recovery Board.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
The files are grouped into one series:
Missing Title
I, General Files, 1929-1954.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Hat, Cap, and Millinery Workers Union Photographs (Photographs #175).
United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union, Millinery Workers Joint Board Records (Wagner #41).
Interview with max Manes in New Yorkers at Work Oral History Collection (OH #1).
United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union Records (Tamiment #54).
Circulars (fliers); New York (N.Y.).; Hat trade |z United States.; Labor -- United States.; Ballots.; Millinery workers |z United States.; Labor union democracy -- New York (State); Correspondence.; Labor unions -- United States.; Newsletters.; Millinery Workers Union; United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union; United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union. Local 8; Lawlor, Martin; Lewis, Marx, 1897-; Greene, Michael F.; United States. National Recovery Administration; Manes, Max
- Series I: General Files, 1929-1954.
  - Africk, J. Louis (Secretary-Treasurer): Letter of Recommendation, Mar 2, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Blocker's Voice(UHC, Local 42 rank and file newsletter), 1947, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - George McLachlan Strike Relief Committee (Danbury, CT): Petition, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Greene, Michael F. (President): Correspondence, 1935, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lawlor, Martin (Secretary-Treasurer): Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lewis, Marx (Acting President): Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Local 8: Election Ballots, 1934-1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Local 8: Elections Circulars, 1929-1946, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Local 8: Financial, undated, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Local 8: Rank and File Circulars, 1930-1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Local 8: Resolutions, 1933-1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Local 24: Rank and File Circulars, 1936-1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Manes, Max (Organizing Committee): Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Manes, Max: Special Convention Delegate Credential, Sep 3, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Manes, Max: Statements, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Men's Hat Department: Declaration of Principles, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Milliner(Local 8 Rank and File Committee newsletter), 1947-1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Millinery and Hatters Committee for Wallace, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Millinery Workers Union Joint Board: Pledge for Cooperation, Sep 1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - National Industrial Recovery Board, Oct 1934 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Needle Trades Workers International Union: Circulars, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Special Convention (UHC), 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 22)